Good evening, an
Добрый вечер
interesting question, there is an adequate
интересный вопрос есть адекватный
reasonable person, they ask such a
человек рассудительный задают такой
question, if you start a special operation to
вопрос вот если начать спецоперация по
protect the Donbass from shelling And now, a
защите Донбасса от обстрелов А теперь
year after it, Belgorod Shebekino will be shelled
через год после нее обстрелит Белгород
there, why
Шебекино там жесть Почему
Well, listen to put it mildly Yes, this is a question
Ну слушайте мягко говоря Да это вопрос
that is now very relevant, why, that is, does
который сейчас очень актуален почему то
nothing  That is, all the time it
ничего не делает если То есть все пора
is being promoted under the sauce that we
пропагандируется под соусом того что мы
must defend our territory there, that is, we
должны там защищать свою территорию то
allow such things Well, yes, there
есть и допускаем такие вещи Ну да
are very big questions why
возникает очень большие вопросы почему
we cannot protect our own
мы не можем защитить свои собственные
cities, that is, from such things.  the
города то есть от таких вещей
army for some reason, that is, it
украинской армии почему то есть она
shells these ordinary living people there.
обстреливает там эти обычные живые
But the question also arises.
Но вопрос тоже возникает То есть как бы
Oh, I don’t know
Ой я не знаю
the thousandth city - It’s just tin Yes,
тысячный город - Это просто жесть Да
even if Carlson would fly there and do it,
хоть Карлсон бы там летал бы и это делал
that is, yes, I agree with you, yes,
то есть это да я с вами согласен можно
there is a question and that’s why I watched the video
да Вопрос есть и поэтому я смотрел видео
there, for example, he says something to himself
там вот например там себе что-то говорит
No one extinguishes No  not firefighters, nothing is
Никто не тушит Нет не пожарных ничего
shorter by
короче
itself That is, under fire, it’s
само собой То есть под обстрелом это
shelling, well, more precisely, extinguishing it, well, it’s
обстреливать ну ой точнее тушить это ну
very risky, therefore,
очень сопряжено с риском поэтому
of course, that is, they are waiting until it
понятное дело то есть они ждут пока там
calms down, left the city, that is, there are
успокоится ушла из города то есть там
marauders, I saw it, yes, that is, I also
мародёры вот видела да то есть я тоже
watched the video today  Yes, there are
сегодня видео смотрел то что да там
cell phone stores below zero Yes, yes, to put it
салоны сотовой связи относится под ноль
mildly, it’s not quite according to
Да да это мягко говоря не совсем по
the plan,
плану
so to speak for me
так говорить для меня
on the protection of Donbass
по защите Донбасса
8 years, like a year has passed here and now
8 лет тут типа проходит год и теперь
with impunity, like the
безнаказанно типа
Belgorod region, this is not only in front of
Белгородская область это не только перед
this guyver,
этим гайвером
but forty-thousandth city of Shebekin
а шебекина сорокатысячный город
Yes, there 36  thousand people lived That
Да там 36 тысяч человек проживало То
is, now they are taking everyone out of there Well,
есть сейчас оттуда всех вывозит Ну да
yes, it’s It’s not just a village there for 1000
это Это не просто там поселок на 1000
people and there Excuse me, there
человек и там Извините меня туалетов
are no toilets Yes, it’s such a yes, that is, it’s such a
нету да это такой да то есть это такой
large city, that is, therefore, yes,
крупный город то есть Поэтому
questions to the current one to our government
да вопросы к действующую к нашему власти
and there is clearly why  this is how it happens Well,
и явно есть почему так происходит
listen, this is all again Well, yes,
Ну слушайте это же опять же все Ну да
even everyone has it There,
нет даже у всех есть Там постоянно у нас
someone constantly asks us why this is happening, that
кто-то спрашивает почему так происходит
is, another question is why, that is, everyone is
то есть другой вопрос почему то есть все
silent And no one should do anything
молчат И никто ничего не делает
What should be done should just
должны Что сделать должны просто все это
finish it all faster  already and just
быстрее закончить уже и просто
establish peace
установить мир
Well, listen Elementary I don’t know That
Ну слушайте Элементарно Я не знаю То
is, sit down at the negotiating table and already there
есть сесть за стол переговоров и уже там
either negotiate the withdrawal of troops or Well, about
либо договариваться выводе войск либо Ну
anything, that is,
о чем угодно то есть просто
it’s just a withdrawal of troops then we’ll talk about
это вывод войск тогда будем говорить о
what else we can
чем мы еще можем
I just know that’s always not
Я просто знаете вот всегда тоже не
I understand why it’s impossible to first
понимаю почему нельзя сначала вот здесь
say at the negotiating table here, well, that
за стол переговоров сказать у нас ну то
is, we, that is, we are ending
есть мы то есть заканчиваем боевые
hostilities Let’s say, relatively speaking,
действия Давайте то есть условно говоря
there at 20 there for 4 hours for 48 hours, that is,
там на 20 там 4 часа на 48 часов то есть
during this time, that is, we
вот в течение этого времени то есть мы
must We propose to withdraw troops  that
должны Мы предлагаем вывести войска то
is, everything is there and we already set
есть и всё то есть и устанавливаем уже
some other conditions there, that is, they are,
там какие-то другие условия то есть они
so first you withdraw troops, that
так что сначала вы выводите войска то
is, of course, there, even if you
есть понятное дело там даже если вот
look at the withdrawal of troops, of course,
смотрите с выводом войска понятное дело
in addition to the withdrawal of troops, we need guarantees for those
помимо вывода войск э нужны гарантии тем
who worked Well, let's say so  our
кто Ну работал скажем так наше
government, which may
правительство которое могут себя
feel somehow in danger. Well, so that
чувствовать как-то в опасности Ну чтобы
they just simply leave now to
они Просто элементарно выехали сейчас с
evacuate these.
этих эвакуировать Давайте
look, we are ready to start, for
что смотрите мы э готовы типа начать
example, there on
например там
June 12, on the Day of Russia, the withdrawal of troops, such as
12 июня в День России вывод войск типа
organized from the territory of Ukraine.
организованные с территории Украины Типа
organizes the departure
организовывает уход
Well, damn it, you understand, I can Want and
Ну блин вы понимаете я-то могу Хотеть и
set any conditions, but I
вот ставить какие угодно условия но я
think our current government is
думаю действующая наша правительство
a little bit and the Ministry of Defense of a different
немножко и Министерство обороны другого
opinion is that in general they believe that
мнения то что в целом они считают что
they have gained a foothold there In the position as a whole,
они закрепились там На позиции в целом
that is, they have mobilized a sufficient
то есть мобилизовали достаточное
number of people there  then
количество там человек то
strengthen the grouping and, on the whole, are ready there,
усилить группировку и в целом готовы там
let’s say, that is, to continue all this, that
допустим еще то есть продолжать все это
is, how much you need me to
то есть Сколько понадобится
voice my opinion that yes,
я вам свое мнение озвучивать то что да
as a resident, it just turns out to you that
как жителя до вас просто получается что
Well, for example, I also see Yes, how
Ну вот я например тоже вот вижу Да как
can the withdrawal of troops from
может остановиться выводом войск из
Ukraine for  in order to
Украины для того чтобы Украина
stop Ukraine, it is only necessary to take Kiev here
остановить надо разве что Киев взять тут
two There are two options yes, that is, either that
два Тут два варианта да то есть либо то
is, our country is withdrawing troops, that is,
есть наша страна выводит войска то есть
and that is, Ukraine is calming down, or that
и то есть Украина успокаивается либо то
is, Our troops are reaching Kiev in
есть Наши войска доходит до Киева в
our country, you are calming down While each of the
нашей страна у вас успокаивает Пока друг
other options here  unfortunately, a year
других вариантов вот к сожалению год
ago there were still options Yes,
назад ещё были варианты Да шутить
it’s possible to joke
возможно
now it’s already quite obvious even if the
сейчас уже совсем очевидно даже если уже
Belgorod region can’t
Белгородская область не могут типа
protect him now, it’s just going
защитить его сейчас идёт
here, it just
тут просто
might be even worse, that is, this
может быть ещё то есть хуже То есть это
prolongation of the conflict is still conditional there for
затягивание конфликт ещё там условно на
two or three years, that is,
два-три года то есть
than  it will be happening not only there in
чем это будет твориться не только там в
one area, that is, I think
одной области То есть я думаю по
along our entire border there we
протяжении всей нашей границы там
had long-range things already give
у нас были дальнобойные вещи уже дают
us Yes, and they will be deeper, but here, yes, that is, all
нам Да и будут глубже но тут да то есть
the more so, I think even taking into account the fact that
тем более я думаю даже с учетом того что
there, although the Americans say  here we are 8
там хотя и американцы говорят вот мы 8
bottom to use there and so on, yes,
низ использовать там и прочее прочее да
that is, it will be used in any case
то есть это в любом случае будет
and I am there again Who
использоваться и я там опять же Кто
shot Carlson there Or someone else, that
стрелял там Карлсон Или кто-то ещё то
is, it will all be said It's not
есть это будет все будут говорить Это не
us and that's all Therefore, yes, just unfortunately
мы и всё Поэтому да просто к сожалению
now  we have the fact that this conflict
сейчас мы имеем то что этот конфликт
can drag on even longer and further And
может ещё дольше и дальше затягиваться И
unfortunately, people will continue to die on the
к сожалению Будут дальше гибнуть люди с
other side a
другой стороны
year ago, so I also
год назад еще вот я вот так тоже
monitor the Telegram of the Russian community
мониторию Telegram сообщества российских
there, these
там вот эти за
telegrams
телеграммов
begin
начинается
with Prigogine Prigozhin, with
с пригожинным Пригожин с
kadyrovka, such begin with everyone
кадыровки такие начинаются у всех
Well  yes, that is, there is a
Ну да то есть есть
squabble, that is, yes there One said something to
грызня то есть да там Один что-то сказал
the other, they didn’t like it, that is,
одно другому это не понравилось это то
everywhere and everywhere That is,
везде и всюду То есть
the situation is not the simplest, you understand,
ситуация не самая простая понимаете
I just see that a year ago We
Просто я так смотрю что год назад У нас
also had some imported
еще было из импортного там какие-то
javelins there  and there weren’t many UFOs, but now it’s already
джавелины и НЛО их немного было а сейчас
shorter Tanks already when a year ago
короче уже Танки уже когда год назад
the plane was fantastic now They
самолет это фантастика была сейчас уже
say directly they’ll let f-16 planes
Прямо говорят дадут самолеты f-16
train these
обучают этих
pilots, that is, gradually, gradually,
пилотов то есть постепенно постепенно
Ukraine is pumping weapons to make these
Украину накачивает оружиями делать эти
technological superiority, that’s all, that’s it,
технологические перевес вот и всё то
but what it is  pumping weapons is,
есть но то что она качка оружием есть
it goes without saying, that is, but how can it be
это само собой то есть но
without it Well, that is, I understand in any
как без этого Ну то есть понимаю в любом
case, even
случае даже вот
the counteroffensive that you have been announced for a long time
контрнаступление которое там у вас давно
there is planned,
там анонсируется планируется
of course, as without the same aviation, that
понятное дело как без той же авиации то
is, in general, go on a counteroffensive
есть Вообще идти на в контрнаступление
because it involves But if  without
потому что это сопряжено Но если без
aviation, that is, with very large losses.
авиации то есть большими очень потерями
Therefore,
Поэтому
if you look at Kherson and Kharkov,
если смотреть Херсон и Харьков
Kharkiv region Well, yes, well, that is,
Харьковская область Ну это да ну то есть
this one
тут этот
definitely, that is, it passed, and there, let’s
безусловно то есть прошло причем там
also say the Kharkov operation, That
допустим тоже харьковскую операцию То
is, you really have very well done
есть у вас действительно очень Молодцы
your military there, that is, very high
ваши там военные то есть очень
quality and everything is great  carried out
качественные и здорово всё провели
done But here already You understand dug in
сделали Но тут уже Понимаете окопались
when it’s already a problem to make it
когда уже это проблема сделать
problematic and here it’s already for sure, that is, they
проблематично и тут уже точно то есть
went around
обошли
here already you understand it will not be possible to say
тут уже понимаете нельзя будет сказать
that 100 people entered there then
то что там зашло там 100 человек
already then you can say
тут уже тогда можно сказать
if they come in like that too you know already then it will be
если так зайдут тоже знаете уже тогда
impossible for the world community not
нельзя будет мировое общественность не
will be able to say that no, it’s like Ukraine
сможет сказать что нет это типа Украина
is not invading,
не вторгается
you and I can only
мы с вами понимаете можем только
argue that what will really happen
рассуждать что что будет по-настоящему
what the same Europe will say to the states
что скажет там та же Европа штатам
Yes and Well, I’m all the rest
Да и Ну я все остальные
I think that all these questions are shelling
Я думаю что эти все вопросы там обстрела
on their own, they are also at an unofficial level
на свои они тоже на неофициальном уровне
everything is negotiated from Europe and with the state
все обговаривается из Европы и со штатом
Well, yes, this is the so-called, you know, too. That
Ну да это так называемые знаете тоже То
is, probing, as we like to
есть прощупывание как у нас любят
say, red lines, that is, there are
говорить красные линии то есть там
a little bit there, a little bit
чуть-чуть там чуть-чуть
there are already lines, I understand there is already something
там уже линии я понимаю там уже что-то
more, let's say, voluminous
более так скажем объёмное
on this  the topic of
на эту тему
the drone is Russia said that you
беспилотника это Россия сказал что
can’t cross the red lines of Ukraine
нельзя переходить красные линии Украины
crossed the Red Square crossed
перешла Красную Площадь пересекла
the Red Square
Красную Площадь
so you
поэтому
know, you and I are here so in the order of the
знаете мы с вами здесь так в порядке
townsfolk we can just
обывателей можем просто обсуждать
discuss what will happen tomorrow who
рассуждать что будет завтра кто его
knows in
знает
the libraries I mean I mean
библиотеках Я имею в виду я имею
only what we are here with  you
исключительно то что мы здесь с вами
are conducting a dialogue, of course, the fact that there is a
ведем диалог понятное дело то что там
huge amount of some kind of operation.
огромное количество операции какие-то
Of course, the fact that you have a huge
Разумеется то что у вас огромное
number of people there supports everything
количество человек там поддерживает всу
there donate in every possible way
там донате всячески то же самое там у
the same there we have fees
нас там сборы проходят То же самое Я там
there  to their own
у меня там ну скажем так не по своей
will, but that is, there are several
воле но то есть есть несколько
mobilized comrades, who are
мобилизованных товарищей вот которым
also there, that is, we are there in every possible way helping
тоже то есть мы там всячески помогаем
there with various parcels
там посылками различными